# Supun Nakandala

Ph.D Student Advanced Data Analytics Lab Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering University of California San Diego

Phone: (+1) 812-558-688

Email: supun.nakandala@gmail.com

Personal Web: scnakandala.github.io

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are in the area of Advanced Data Analytics which is at the intersection of Machine Learning, Scalable Data Processing Systems and Human Computer Interaction. My current projects involve implementing Deep Learning powered Data Management Systems/Abstractions which can handle analytical queries on dark data types (e.g. images, videos, time series data) along with structured data in a scalable fashion.

### **EDUCATION**

Sep 2017 - Present

Ph.D Student(Computer Science & Engineering) University of California San Diego
Member of the Advanced Data Analytics Lab & advised by Prof. Arun Kumar

Jun 2010 - Apr 2015

BSc.Eng(Hon's) (Computer Science & Engineering) University of Moratuwa - Sri Lanka
Cumulative GPA: 4.11/4.20

Ranked first in a batch of 100 students specializing Computer Science & Engineering.

## **SELECTED PUBLICATIONS**

**Nakandala, S.**, Kumar, A., "Feature Materialization Trade-offs for Scalable Transfer Learning with Deep ConvNets". [Under Preparation]

May 2017 Nakandala, S., Giovanni, C., Norman, S., Ahn, Y., "Gendered Conversation in a Social Game-Streaming Platform". [The 11th International AAAI Conference On Web

And Social Media (ICWSM-17)] (pdf: https://goo.gl/FaOlXW, presentation: https:

//goo.gl/68eZoS)

Oct 2016 Nakandala, S., Gunasinghe, H., Marru, S., Pierce, M. "Apache Airavata Security Man-

ager: Authentication and Authorization Implementations for a Multi-Tenant eScience Framework". In Proceedings of *IEEE 12'th International Conference on eScience 2016*. (pdf:

https://goo.gl/51Ttm2)

Jul 2016 Nakandala, S., Pamidighantam, S., Yodage, S., Doshi, N., Abeysinghe, E., Kankanamalage,

C.P., Marru, S. and Pierce, M. "Anatomy of the SEAGrid Science Gateway". In Proceedings of Extreme Science & Engineering Discovery Environments Conference on Diversity, Big Data,

and Science at Scale 2016 (XSEDE) (p. 40). ACM. (pdf: https://goo.gl/oytirb)

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

May 2015 - Aug 2015 Teaching Assistant for Operating Systems Course (CS 2042), CSE-UoM.

The objective of this course was to provide fundamental knowledge in Operating Systems to computer science students. My tasks included providing instructions for the labs and grading assignments.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Oct 2015 - Aug 2017 Research Software Developer - Science Gateways Research Center, Indiana University

Program committee member and core developer in the Apache Airavata project which is a science gateway middleware framework that enables users to compose, manage, execute, and monitor large scale applications and workflows on distributed computing resources such as local clusters, supercomputers, computational

grids, and computing clouds.

May 2014 - Sep 2014 Google Summer of Code Intern for Apache Airavata

Before this work Airavata did not support security capabilities for communication between Airavata based gateways and the Airavata server. In this project I implemented security capabilities to Airavata thrift services

and clients (link: https://goo.gl/4qAS3X).

May 2013 - Sep 2013 Google Summer of Code Intern for phpMyAdmin

Refactored the SQL executor and column structure manipulation code in phpMyAdmin, which is an open-

source web based interface for the MySQL databases (link: https://goo.gl/JNk3vM).

## **AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS**

Aug 2015 IBM Gold Medal for the Best Academic Performance in Computer Science & Engineering

- University of Moratuwa.

May 2014 Scholarship to attend 4<sup>th</sup> South Asia Workshop (2014) on Research Frontiers in Com-

puting - NUS School of Computing

Aug 2010 - Apr 2015 Mahapola Higher Education Merit Scholarship for Undergraduate Studies - Government

of Sri Lanka.

Nov 2009 Award for the Most Outstanding Student - De Mazenod College (High School).

Mar 2009 President's Scout (Eagle Scout Equivalent) - Sri Lanka Scout Association.

# EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

2014 Membership Co-Chair, ACM Student Chapter - University of Moratuwa.

2011 Editor, Sri Lanka University Catholic Students Movement.

2008 Head Prefect, De Mazenod College (High School).